Becca Nelson Bailey

Chicago, IL
beccanelson.is
→ hello@beccanelson.is
beccanelson
be.net/rebeccanelson

About Me

I developed an interest in technology after spending a few years as an elementary fine arts teacher. I am currently a Software Crafter at 8th Light, and love helping fellow artists and career changers understand software. My focus as a developer is on front-end design and development, where I can use my experience in design and fine arts to help designers and developers work together.

Technical Skills

AngularJS (2+) ★★★☆
React ★★★★

HTML+CSS ★★★☆
Java (Spring) ★★★☆

Vue.js ★★☆☆☆

Rub

Ruby + Rails 🛨 ដំបំជំជំ

Experience

8th Light - Chicago, IL - April 2016-Present

Resident Apprentice - April 2016—November 2016 Software Crafter - November 2016—June 2018 Lead Software Crafter - June 2018—Present

Code As a full-stack developer, I care about using the best tools available to solve technical problems. But when I'm building software that is being used by real people, I am especially interested in the user-facing parts of our applications, and continually learning how to use front-end development and design to create the best possible experience for the user.

Team building As a consultant, it's very common to discover that the technical problem we are trying to solve is actually a people problem. I have led successful planning meetings and retros, participated in hiring decisions, and I am always learning to give effective feedback and build stronger development teams.

Mentoring As a former teacher, my favorite part of my job is mentoring and sharing my knowledge. I mentored an apprentice throughout most of 2018, and am a PDM (Professional Development Manager) for three junior-level developers.

Diversity and I am the chair of 8th Light's Diversity, Culture and Inclusion committee, which is seeking to improve company policies around diversity, specifically as they relate to the recruitment, retention, and advancement of people in underrepresented groups in technology.

Data and Research Panelist - Ingenuity - Chicago, IL - September 2016—June 2018

Ingenuity is a non-profit organization that supports fine arts programs in the Chicago Public Schools. Each year, Ingenuity collects data on fine arts programs across the city, and uses that data to create an online guide called the artlook map. I served on an advisory panel that focused on Ingenuity's collection and use of data to improve fine arts education.

Music and Fine Arts Teacher - Various - January 2011—June 2015

Given the opportunity, I would love to tell you more about my experiences teaching both in the United States and overseas. I have taught both as a full-time teacher in one school and a traveling teaching artist at multiple schools.

Speaking

RVA Javascript JavaScript Survival Skills

Richmond, VA November 2018

Chicago JS Camp JavaScript Survival Skills (recording pending)

Chicago, IL September 2018

Education and Training

Dev Bootcamp Completed 19-week web development program focused on full-stack Chicago, IL development, including Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, web servers, database September 2015 - January 2016 management, and courses in Engineering Empathy.

Anderson University Bachelor of Music in Music Education

August 2006 - May 2010

Anderson, IN Anderson University Honors Program